We like to be led. Doesn't it feel good
every once in a while for somebody to
take charge? And it doesn't have to be
you. How many of you are over your
company or over your division or you're
over your small business or you're over
your family? You're over something.
Don't you just love it sometimes when
somebody's like, "Here's what we're
doing. Here's when we're doing it. Don't
ask about it." You're like, "That's kind
of cool." You'll marry somebody like
that. I'm serious. Just it just feels
good sometimes when you're over a lot
and somebody will just decide. How many
of you like to be led
like to be led?
Now you have a mental model of what it
means to be led and it's based on
technology.
Your mental model of God in a modern
context is the woman on the GPS
who makes suggestions.
If you don't do what she tells you to
do, she doesn't stop the car.
But God will
because he's a shepherd.
>> A good shepherd. What's a good shepherd?
That's what Jesus said in John 10:11. If
you want to look up the reference, he
said, "I am the good shepherd." All that
other stuff, he's that, too. But he is a
good shepherd.
So that must mean that he knows
something I don't know
and that he's going to get me there
sometimes against my own human will
>> or my sorry y'all, fleshly desires. It
just had to be one side or the other. I
just chose y'all. There is no spiritual
significance to that. Everybody on this
side of the room looks so hurt, y'all.
Maybe we'll switch it up next week or
something. I don't know. And uh I
thought about
would it be a good GPS system in my car
if if when I made the wrong turn it was
like, okay, cool.
Would it be a good GPS?
And then I thought about, would it be a
good uh physical trainer
if when you came in and you said, "I
don't feel like it." They were like,
"Great. I I don't really feel like
training you either. Let's eat
and let's eat sugar and let's eat crap."
Cuz I really don't feel like counting
your reps today either. So, we're both
on the same page. Let's go.
Would it be
would it be a good God
if he didn't put conviction
alongside comfort?
>> And is what you're going through in your
life right now a correction not from the
devil but from the good shepherd?
>> Do we give the devil credit for the
shepherd's directions?
Everything bad that happens is the
devil. Not necessarily.
>> He's a good shepherd.
Now
that we've had that New Testament
perspective, let's go to the Old
Testament. The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want. He's going to direct
me. You remember all the things it says,
green grass, still waters restoreth my
soul. His rod and his staff, they
comfort me. That's verse four. Put up
verse four real quick. His rod, thy rod,
talking to God. Thy rod and thy staff,
they comfort me.
I love comfort and I need comfort. And
sometimes I need God to hold me cuz I
won't let anybody else touch me. I'm
serious. Sometimes I'm defensive in ways
that God's the only one who can get in.
And I love that he can and he can
comfort me. And sometimes there's a gap
when I'm like, I don't get this and I'm
glad God can comfort me. And sometimes
I'm nursing my own wounds and I'm
licking my own wounds and I'm I'm making
it worse as I'm doing it. So I need the
bomb of Gilead to come and comfort me.
And I'm thankful that he comforts me.
But in the passage, the Lord is my
shepherd. I shall not want. That means I
lack no good thing.
That means the shepherd knows the
difference between what feels good and
what is good.
>> The next part is the part that most of
us struggle with because the first thing
that God does as the shepherd, the Lord
is my shepherd. I shall not want verse
two. You won't like this part now that
you look at it this way. He maketh me.
He makes me. I don't like you to make
me. I don't like you to make me. And yet
the first thing that he says the
shepherd does, he makes me lie down.
Hold on, God. I want you to be my
shepherd. I want to be led where I want
to be led
because my mental model of God is GPS.
So I'll tell you the destination.
If I get off track, then put me back on,
but take me another way because God, the
Lord is my Alexa.
The Lord is my Siri.
>> The Lord is my
>> shepherd.
>> A what?
>> A good shepherd.
>> That means he's not going to see you
doing something that he knows where it
leads and not say something to you about
it.
>> That means he's not going to let you
sabotage yourself and your future
without bringing correction. But see, we
don't really like that side of the
shepherd. It's like, no, no, no. I
expect God to direct me. So here's what
I want. Opportunities. Okay. What if a
part of the opportunity God is going to
bring you in two years is the character
development of a disappointment that he
takes you through right now.
Is he still
your shepherd
>> when you don't like what he says? Is he
fire your trainer if they never tell you
something to do you don't like. Fire
your friends if they'll never tell you
the truth. When you're making a fool of
yourself. You ever look back at pictures
of stuff you wore and say, "Where were
my friends? I had no friends." It's
scary. Nobody told me. That was so
tight.
It wasn't flattering. Let me tell you,
it was tight and I wasn't toned. And
nobody said anything about that
contrast.
He makes me his correction.
I used to teach leadership a lot more
than I do now. I don't know why I don't
teach it as much anymore, but maybe I
should start back cuz I would teach.
When somebody corrects you, that's an
investment.
>> Now, I don't mean people that don't know
you, people that just insult you, people
that just are spouting their opinion.
Get that out of your mind. The Lord is
my shepherd. When you are led by
somebody and they love you enough, yes,
Jesus loves me. Yes, Jesus loves me.
Yes, Jesus loves me. How do I know this?
I know he loves me not only because the
Bible tells me so. I know Jesus loves me
because Jesus leads me.
>> And when he leads me, sometimes he uses
a staff to bring me back.
>> That staff doesn't feel good around the
sheep's neck.
Why you always associate God with a good
feeling?
Sometimes you got to sit in something
you don't like to get to something that
you want. Whether that's peace or joy.
All my shouts went out the door. Lord,
they were shouting so good 10 minutes
ago.
New song just came to me.
Cuz when he brings you back, that's
kindness.
>> It's the kindness of God that brings me
to repentance.
because I expect to be led by somebody
who knows what's out ahead and I don't
>> cuz I'm crazy.
>> I'm crazy.
I will get so in what I want to feel
right now that I will reach for
something now that I'm going to regret
later unless I have a shepherd.
So, I might as well tell you I need
Jesus. No apologies. I need Jesus. Yeah.
Yeah, me too. I need Jesus to forgive me
so I can go to heaven when I die. Uh-uh.
I need Jesus way before I get to heaven
when I die.
>> The Lord is my
>> talk to me. He's my
>> shepherd. Oh, I love green grass. But do
you like when he makes you lie down?
>> I want to get the green grass.
>> All right. So, I I I give you for my own
life. When I preach about things for my
own life, I don't want you to think
that's because I think my life is so
important. It just makes it more real to
me.
>> If I open a sermon illustration book and
say, "Okay, in the year 1376, a guy said
this." I don't even know if he really
said that or not. That's just in the
book. This is what I know is real. Okay?
And maybe you can relate.
Two or three times in the last I would
say in the last couple of years,
I felt like the Lord was saying inside
of me, this never out loud for me. I
have never heard God speak to me out
loud ever. And I've asked him to before
because then I would know,
especially if he said it like Morgan
Freeman on Shaw Shank Redemption. I'd be
like, "Oh, that's God right there.
That's Morgan Freeman. That's the voice
of God."
So
inside there there was a few times and
I'll tell you what they were because I
think it I think it helps to flesh it
out a little bit. When when I started
doing what Paul said in Galatians,
trusting in the flesh, that's my own
human strength. He was saying God
started something in your life and then
you're like, "Oh, thanks God. I'm good.
I've got it from here."
That's what we do with the Lord. I call
it divinity on demand.
We're like, "God, I want you for season
1, but I'll take season 2, season 3,
season 4. I got it from here." And you
don't got it from here. And you don't
know you don't got it from here until
the plot twist happens that you didn't
see because you didn't write the script.
But God did. And he's the shepherd. And
that's why you have to trust him. Not
only to save you, watch this, but
sustain you. There is a saving faith. I
throw myself on the mercy of God. I
throw myself on the grace of the cross
of Christ and that saves me and is done.
But that same grace, don't think that
you get that grace and then just grind
it out the rest of your life. Don't
think you just pray to God, parents, and
say, "God, give us a healthy baby. Okay,
we got it from here. We'll raise them
from here." No, you won't. You're crazy.
You're crazy. If you really think you
can do this whole human experience
without Jesus, you're crazy. Are you
crazy?
Are you crazy?
You stopped tithing because the economy
was bad. Are you crazy?
>> No. I got it from here. God, you blessed
me with this, but God, I'm going to keep
it now. Are you crazy?
>> So God gave it to you, and now you want
to grind it out.
>> Are you crazy?
>> So here's where the Lord showed me. I
was making a sermon and I was figuring
out what to call it. And I know that the
Lord gave me a title. I can feel it when
the Lord tells me what to call it. So if
he tells me to call it He's still the
shepherd, I call it that. And you're
like, "Okay, cuz I know I could do
sexier than that. I know. I know I could
do better clickable than that." You
know, how to navigate seasons of regret
to lead to breakthroughs, more sex, more
money, and fat loss. That would be
clickable.
And that's fine. There's a time for all
of that. There is a time to be
strategic. There really is. There is a
time to dial it in. There's a time
technically to figure all of that out.
But all that comes after after. But when
I'm preparing to preach to you, see, I
can't do that in my flesh.
>> I need the spirit.
>> And God gave me something and I said, I
can't call it that.
It won't get clicked.
And it I this is not a conversation. I'm
trying to make it a conversation because
it can't I can't say it to you how God
God speaks on the level of spirit, not
the level of flesh. So we're trying to
tell you how it went. It felt inside of
me like God said, "Is this what we've
come to?"
>> Clicking.
Is this what we've come to?
So you won't preach what I tell you is
going to help people and set them free
that you really know in your spirit.
You're talking about clicks,
talking about practice.
And I really felt like God didn't like
it. In fact, I almost felt like God
said, "I hate this.
I can't bless this.
>> I can't work with this.
>> You're going to try to figure out in the
flesh what can only be done through the
spirit?"
>> So,
well, I don't do that. I don't put
sermons on YouTube. I think you missed
the point.
>> I think we all do it all the time.
>> We try to figure out what people would
like.
>> Are you crazy?
>> Cuz they're crazy. Now you're trying to
base your life around crazy people. And
what crazy people will like will lead to
a level of crazy that is crazier than
your original crazy that made you try to
impress crazy people.
>> And then you forget who you are.
>> You forget who you are.
You forget, man. I'm not up here to be a
performer.
>> I'm a preacher, baby.
>> And the spirit of the Lord is upon me
because he has anointed me to preach
good news to the captives and recovery
of sight for the blind and the breaking
of chains and the liberation of those
who are oppressed and the acceptable
year of the Lord's favor.
Now, do you want favor or flesh?
>> You want to do it God's way? I preached
this last week. God's ways seem weird,
but they work.
>> It works to trust God. It works to give
it to him. It works to step out in
faith. It works to stay in faith. It
works to speak faith. It works to hear
faith. Faith comes by hearing, hearing
by the word. And then you get stuck in
the space of trying to figure out in the
flesh what God started by the spirit.
Hey, thanks for stopping by my YouTube
channel. I hope you were blessed today.
If you were share this with somebody,
like and subscribe and leave me a
comment. Let me know where you're
watching from, what we can pray for you
about. Hope to see you back here again
really soon.
[Music]